- name your channel ad stop with such as
pass material nasha Nagaraj the way my
Caravaggio Maria cutoff parodied
Borowski yon Edisto at the Palmer guy at
one store savonia - Guevara
meditate su problema militancy fix
about you okay and we're broadcasting
from Diamond Mountain University this is
the I think it's the largest retreat
center in United States versus amakuni
retreat center sitting on the start of
American we tried to find the most empty
place in America tiniest of American so
we have thirty beautiful meditation
cabins receiveth to make up to meet at
sea in the desert in Arizona whose thing
about Sonya and in the desert you have
to have a cowboy hat what is done in
Austin I see the Cowboys car shop course
Napa and you gotta have cowboy boots
those live with but Cena kicking voice
kill
so we're hoping all the Cowboys in
Arizona we meditate with our boots on
Sam wake up boy what is only material
but simcha and with our cowboy hats you
boys could level it's good if you have a
cowgirl is Cowboys crazy over stuff
all right so we're gonna talk about
typical problems in meditation the
problem of five problems in meditation
and you know you expect if there are
five problems and and we're gonna go for
one hour I'm so if you if there are five
classical problems in meditation yes yes
problem minutes in everybody gets these
five promise it doesn't matter what
country you live in every human mind
that meditates cause they just keep you
will have these five problems and it's
interesting if there are five problems
you expect five solutions right yes this
problem most not sure that that's a
shame but there's eight solutions Mary
Cheney Voisin okay five problems it's
solutions
very famous okay and we just finished
the last hour we call 1919 means
experiential explanation of the problems
when she launched a tabula Shinya
problem and practical and we actually
did a meditation together for one hour
I didn't we tried to repeat the problems
in the actual meditation substance
immediate action so I have a suggestion
for Tim a CIA director Michael nice
proportionately t-midi wreck tracer in
the next hour for our Gold Club
broadcast the junior silver chalices
yeah primo if here at the national
called Koba
will be describing the problems from the
ancient book mobile my piece of the
problem is three Emily technique but I
suggest that we will send
down Mamiya can translate your estimate
Oh Maria morbid obesity there's a
one-hour meditation you can do I didn't
ask much details to go through the nine
stages of meditation and you go through
all the problems related to the same
David start immediately
it produced a problem oh and you learn
how to fix them your boot is nice
colorful his privates
so we'll be we'll be posting that unlike
in the next by tomorrow night all right
and we'll put it up online so you can
actually practice these problems and how
to fix them so today I'll just talk
about them but I encourage all the go
Club members yeah gene IDs of safely on
the gold COBOL do the actual meditation
who did what's the meditation we used
cocoon we did that so makes possible
Tomlin which is giving people comfort
taking away their problems the Yanni
illudium comforter is the bear Anya we
need problem who did we do that tongue
land on Nicole me do a little Glen on
yourself there's a special Tony you can
do
yes sob dumpling cuz their most ideals
if you have an important meeting if you
have to give a teaching this afternoon
it's very helpful in morning watching
Polly is the autumn weather Dean do the
tone line on yourself still on Glen is
some hours ago
in the afternoon and then the afternoon
me this afternoon will get a big
injection of energy from the morning me
back then what Nimoy yeah Buddhism
fellowship a groom
energy at Minya Kotori ultram do vegetal
sir
so in that one meditation online vietnam
is it that same line you can learn to do
this helping yourself later in the day
meditation the s'mores no chief mimosa
mimosa beer who do seem normal evasion
and at the same time you can experience
all the meditation problems that i'm
going to talk about three most types
problem so we're in the middle of an AC
i teacher training facility in Adrienne
good Lisa
the students here in Arizona at the
retreat center is this to us every treat
center which is completely fold this
week there's not any other place to stay
in the pose diss epona need a lenient
novice about no minister even all the
Bears and the wild pigs we asked them to
move out with McSweeney so I'm gonna
actually go through the actual homework
questions yeah but I did series both of
them are thereabouts and that way you
can finish your homework off about them
and I have exciting news for all the
russian-speaking audience listening oh
is that listening all still a closed
case it is a closure we are making plans
for a CI teacher training in Europe we
plan you don't a separate images to
label wrote them and there'll be a
Russian language music so purposely we
arranged for Russian woman to marry a
German guy by the home with Selena
travel in Arkansas elaborate ruse
creationist esq Cheney and they are
cooperating they got married here
actually
so we'll be starting those programs soon
it's Gordon with the program understand
okay so here we go first of the five
meditation problems the Tibetan word I
don't know everyone likes it around the
whole world say lay low lay low
it sounds like what it is what does it
mean lazy slob yeah okay our chamber
horse okay so it's very similar okay
so lay low means okay now listen when
you teach it this is a teacher training
right this not really don't call it
laziness nian is divisive Alenia okay
put on your second husband second way
accent is positive accent erosion a
second wife I don't feel like meditating
today yeah you choose to see what if
actually deteriorate
I didn't have a good sleep last night
young useful is watching I had a fight
with my husband yesterday
I'm very busy
oh my stomach a little bit upset then
the first meditation problem is making
excuses why you don't have to meditate
today Daniel movies and it sounds like
that I don't
yes II wouldn't if I to me I don't feel
like meditating today Jimmy did you ever
see what's the last sentence that mine
always says just before they go to
breakfast margarita - imperium coitus
after Koerner so gang got it so young
but tomorrow I would definitely minute
ok guys does it sound familiar
there are 4 solutions - yes a Malayalam
say depe timber solution Dibby Dibby the
mature oak a very famous ok that's why
you have 8 solutions to five problems
because the first problem has four
solutions of a problem material singing
the first problem has the has the three
extra solutions we have a problem is
three the politician
ok Peppa
ok Peppa in sanskrit is shredder
shudders Papa Rooskies nothing we're
hard SRD certain in English cardiac same
same rude
cardi CRD surd certain same as in
Russian and the words father comes from
theater shut up
so Russian is very close to which is
very cool so Russian speakers you are
super cool it's easier for you to learn
sounds good sure it means faith faith
okay you have faith but special meaning
of faith not as so biznitch engineering
okay and when I explained the four
solutions to the first problem I like to
talk about your high school you know
school okay and it happened to me in
high school some lost corner you see a
nice-looking girl in school
remember our fiftieth anniversary anyway
how does it happen in high school first
dude you look at the girl
macho this model it's an idea order boy
she's pretty cool and in your mind
Mia you are making a list we system
later okay
Oh her hair is cool oh she's body so
cool yellow car I see her voice is so
cool cool and when she likes them is so
cool
so this is how you're supposed to think
about meditation don't do it oh okay
people who meditate they're so calm
they can focus their mind I knew what
was the focus you know it yeah always
smiling I need alibis they always wear
cowboy hat I need sit down lots of
cowboys coach level just kidding you
chew okay and they do better business
also
I knew business okay because they can
focus on on things for problem-solving
meditation is fantastic and for
controlling your emotions in your
business it LeConte rally of any emotion
business
meditation is incredible the businessman
or businesswoman who doesn't get upset
when the business has a problem will
become super cool business persons
businessman or businesswoman Catherine
near as travels activist Nikhil problem
of businesses a super Kruti businessman
a businesswoman on and much more wealthy
and you know it's not the goal of life
to collect money we just nick nick are
our teacher just had a baby a few days
ago right I was there I refused to come
in the room when the baby come out but
just after I come in the room so I I can
stay I'm sure that you come into this
life naked recorded Sapna's only me and
you go out of this life naked you don't
carry money and when it's time to go you
have to leave the money Ramiro to
achieve actually small separating and
you're naked but no if you have focused
yes no was focus you can be more
successful in this life and you can help
more people
meditation can help you become
financially successful and before you
leave naked if it is simple we do it so
that not only you can help more people
my diamond business boy I'll mostly
business I think a total we spent five
million dollars on saving the ancient
books five million u.s. dollar I didn't
ask Rania driven ethnic so it's useful
to make money and this broadcast is
being done for the gold club Russian
speakers in fear Qatari videos lately
and I'm called Clovis a pitch there from
Russia Ukraine Kazakhstan other
countries I see you crying because I
found it a druggie strap that's why I
put the Ukrainian and Russian national
colours on my script I see what you
little basket Oh crying skin and sauna
and a flop
yo ski and so those people listening to
this broadcast
luiz de cataluña fear they have a club
of over 1000 people know when you see a
lot of Ukrainian people they're all
donating at least $1.00
and if see any minute endure per month
cars the music and so far they have
raised more than $100,000 180 yeah
[Applause]
and John Brady over there we have the
same air conditioning NASA Tanaka we can
get Sonya and we spent together we spent
32 years treated vaca-oom of nice Usha
saving the ancient books
they have employed all the ancient books
from ancient India 4600 books is at
least Nico 3 of me easy in division of
computer they're online they're free I
need those appear online and we are
translating them ok and we are they
found they just found 300,000 books in
Mongolia and if told customers didn't
know what 3 statistic Mongolia and
Cristina kacica
and we also have some of our Sanskrit
experts here today so I have a very
strong international team sceneline it's
not okay come on then and because of the
Gold Club help me she called Koba they
can feed their kids where's your kid
I need small good karma okay so
of course we have to our staff works I
don't know like 90 hours a week Marcia
start reading care about the given hasta
to soft needs you know we pay them like
ten cents an hour
they sit scent of chess but it has even
the ten cent have to come from someplace
so we're very grateful and we have many
many refugees you know see some watching
Minogue isn't in India they are typing
the ancient books I new voice video and
we have a very cool project in Europe on
a C's class thing which is for the
refugees from countries like Syria
Afghanistan Iraq Syria Afghanistan and
they are learning a skill to support
themselves and their families
I believe there are one of the first
refugees in Europe to legally work on
their new skill which is sewing we teach
them how to use sewing machine the
agency cut really Ghana is a child
we brought they know we now look I knew
just the sheets they are using sewing
machine to make book covers for the
engine books and easily machine digital
services device
applause kissed cannula driven ethnic
and we are paying them in we and they
have to make three hundred thousand book
covers um doesn't it says that's 300
South trees the trees applause Trista T
sister okay
and the director of that project is here
nor
can you come up here I thought you might
like to see where all that money's going
to see what she's doing here is our
Sanskrit Act expert Aisha and her three
- Aisha her son you're seen Kylie
because of your help were able to pair
stuff Thank You Kari his dad has another
project oh you've all pop with
recuperate where's his dad they got
permission from the government of Mexico
I need sugar as a senior private to
start training 23 million children my
chest was six three million of the tea
so the Congress has voted to support it
Congress there will be teaching kids to
drink healthy green drinks that always
alone in that big kid in the morning
each kid will get a great drink because
obesity childhood obesity - fat oh but
how much does it yes it has spread in
Mexico Mexico strenuous from the United
States is America so I think over 50% of
kids are overweight and they will get
they will get diabetes
they all have heart problems any fires a
problem a system they will die young we
already know their future and it spread
to China
American food candy candy Jim Bakker
20,000 shops in opened in China and they
are teaching kids to eat bad food yes
you do
I think there's a McDonald's in the
Kremlin near the Kremlin I saw it
teaching Russian kids to eat that which
is okay so this is very good for your
meditation
it's a Watterson okay eat well have a
green drink every morning cause the
woods alone and a people you don't need
to eat a big breakfast soy lattes after
and they will help your yoga I'm sorry
okay so first quality to fix lay low
yakisoba mochi is privately I don't feel
like meditating today yeah
think about how cool it's gonna be when
you learn too many to do I do my set on
car class and the budget cut down now
it's like admiring a girl in your high
school
about sights do scoffs :
then what's the second step in the high
school roof that was shocked Scalia you
have to decide I want that girl widow's
made you see yeah quite sure that your
school that's called dimbo it's the
second solution to laziness it of Tarawa
senior clean it's the second solution to
I don't feel like meditated but I've
devil a manatee tomorrow cynic problem
young chui's touch to her choice 20
minute
laughter besides Shakespeare said see if
tomorrow and tomorrow and tomorrow
creeps in this petty pace from day to
day to the last syllable of recorded
time it means your tomorrow tomorrow
tomorrow okay so second solution edition
yeah I want it I want that girl who's
the girl good meditation oh wow
looks cool I can get rich I can get
peaceful I can help other people
oh my hope is about Gotham Spa coin them
I can help other people I want that yeah
okay that's a decision okay admire it
Abashidze and decide to get it a
petrosini positive okay then with the
girl in the high school that teams the
escapes :
there's a special system yes the subway
system so 100 years ago when I was in
high school we don't have online
anything we don't have computers so we
have to carry books each class has a
separate book and those books are heavy
and thick design it's an illusion of
Allah didn't know koneko nice it's Nikki
what she told it to Jolie
so you get a big test Arad notebook
tetrad big notebook for all your classes
one one to keep all your notes
then you have a big nose and you put
that you pile the books on it you walk
around the school like this it was cause
it seemed I could squash : okay now how
do you meet a girl
that you chose her and you want her
really Catherine you arranged to go
around the corner when she comes around
the corner and you bang tetrapods all
the books and then she won't get down
she was like then you have to say I'll
help you I hope you suppose here's your
boy do you want to go out with me on
Friday so the third solution is do
something do something
I can't work hard but it is work hard to
get militants but it is service to
approach it every day I don't care how
you feel you have no with Sebastian
if you feel good meditation if you feel
bad just do your meditation if you had a
good sleep
do your meditation if you had a bad
snake blocker spider
do your meditation if your body feels
great deal way she shuts the cloth do
your meditation if your bag hurts in
your leg hurts and it's time it hurts do
your goddamn you should do it
understand that's number three if you do
that you're gonna get the date you're
gonna get ah we buy goods in a civilian
at the jumpin
his restaurant on camera bag Avenue
opens Kirsten like a cool TV new was it
Japanese Mongolian ski even then I had a
scene even at that time I had a seat
from Manali Mongolian yeah and then if
you're so nice okay that first it's so
beautiful and that's the fourth
correction to laziness little yeah
because you work hard in your meditation
school kavoussi robotics famous that's
right you knocked down her books many
times then you get to go on the date
then you go to the garden it's sad and
it feels so nice Shin Jung Shi Jong Shin
Jang means your mind and your body are
really strong to meditate it does not
change the watch it cela a wash oh she
lived let me do that sir
you did your yoga the only yoga you
drank your green drink you you meditate
many times you suffer right Ichi Shoku
and then you get the result and when you
sit down to meditate
it's like someone giving you a massage
of your mind and your body that your
ideal like massage or myself
you sit down to meditate you're like a
pyramid
and the mind feels totally happy oh my
she shares a palmist okay that's the
fourth correction - I'll meditate
tomorrow it swarthy antidote we
have a problem because you want him
anything
you are making excuses to manatee like
in the afternoon you like maybe I could
just do a little bit more I mean I
finished my meditation this morning yeah
that quenches time you thought so Audra
I did a good hour for me this year and
it tells always doing there with yoga I
don't know I didn't reach this level yet
but in the afternoon he was he and John
Brady yesterday you sneak outside do
some more poses after that yoga class
you write poses I notify you again if
mrs. John embrace officially is shown
him no scope I do a yoga nasty ash just
zoo mashhad she she's real crazy yeah
okay so the fourth correction to
laziness then you get addicted to
meditation and that's a good addiction
we finished the first problem and we
finished the first problem solution
which has four parts okay tepid symbol
so well ginger ginger okay you you
admire that thing vomiting or to get it
you work hard to get it and spill their
books but we see that about it there's
still a couple cheats Rania a technique
yet and then you get the result is the
Mongolian dinner and afterwards
we apologize she's Carly resisted using
my words khmer surin ifs and you feel it
feels so good then you don't have that
problem anymore somebody says let's
meditate tomorrow I'm doing it today
Francis come on let's just melt it
tomorrow like why wait till tomorrow
let's do some extra attention does that
serve I see what you sure that's this
afternoon okay like that okay
all right second problem this is a
famous code word secret word it is my
secret as for Thamud Japanese I forgot
the instruction of my teacher that's the
second problem yes that will instruct
sis we were cheated after a problemo I
forgot my teachers meditation
suggestions for me that's it that's the
second problem problem but what it means
is you lost in your meditate during your
meditation you lost the object which
your teacher gave you so the one of the
first important things in meditation is
selecting your meditation object for
today
and that's why it's so important to have
a meditation teacher right we'll talk
wash them it's okay for me to pass and
they will give you a suggestion I know
you have important meeting today
yes nature so I suggest you meditate
tonglen on yourself in the afternoon but
0 is subordinate on Glenn my voice to be
a Buddhist so what's the meditation
object
Bobbi Expedia Dodson yeah my nervous
this afternoon me that yet
minotaurs at nearly yakitori buddhism
near nature and that's your meditation
object so you close your eyes you know
and you say okay my teacher gave me a
meditation I'm supposed to meditate
about my this South afternoon yeah
Kotori your Moodle and you focus on
Michael in the afternoon and after one
minute by magic look at em again it
changes into panchak punch in Russian :
Jerome yo John okay like here's Michael
Michael in the afternoon then suddenly
he changed to Russian donut those key
points you I got it
that's the second meditation problem
this afternoon Michael changed into a
Russian donut and you're not sending
Michael energy anymore you are planning
how to get a donut after meditation
Buddhism in there give a planner its
punching okay then you have to apply
this fifth correction which is the
correction to the second problem in fact
every minute tateshina cough thyroid
problem in Wisconsin and it's called
chamber September okay so in Arizona
where we are right now what is the
message has in this area all the Cowboys
grow cows that's why they call cowboy
see a cowboy meatiest cut off in the
fight
boy so they keep cars and actually they
let them go in the desert you know some
really cut post I'll buy these books
once a year they collect them I need
cigarettes okay the collection method is
very interesting methods for a cut off
which is insidious you get a big cow
truck you drive through the deserts flow
you have a big bag of carrot soup
Markovic and you go carrot and you throw
and then the cows that I can come to get
the carrots Co you can have a second
carrot just get in the truck it's kind
of stuff I watch him doing it there's
always wanted to cause very similar to
word if suggest Baraka of kateri pod
omnivore do when you ask them to do they
don't want to do then that cowboy
hesitate to have a rope Lhasa it's
colossal yeah and you throw it at the
car and it goes over their head and then
you it takes a lot of strength
now your mind is just like a wild cow
but Vova you are the cowboy that's why
it's important to meditate with your
cowboy hat on is the materials Cowboys
push nation when your mind goes to the
doughnut that point then you have to
catch him
by much pull it back even to this
afternoon's Michael Anna brodnik abierta
catimor Mike look at our Buddha
Shinyoung so the Tibetan word timber
timber it means pull that rope come back
here
Boucher sir you can I promise you you
can have a doughnut after many type
ramen I be sure we share posting it
that's the power just punch it
no green Jing for you honey I promise
you big doughnut I be SharePoint you
will make any toilet drink the green
drink and I told to drink the green then
you pull your mind back now I'll tell
you a meditation trick and I we talked
about it this money yes well but Kivar
you don't fight with your mind you will
lose
okay talk to your mind persuade your
mind
yeah donut is great is delicious and I
promise we'll eat one after meditation
so that's decided so you don't have to
think about anymore I don't like Yong
Yong goo I'm telling you the truth
you will get a donut after meditation
mostly meat that's it follow just punch
it so don't worry about it
don't forget we have a meeting this
afternoon is that one sec you know we
gotta get ready for this media let's get
back to it okay so talk to your mind
voice it doesn't work to fight
you have to persuade your mind if you
say don't think about honest don't think
about doughnuts once again nobody in the
world likes to be told what to do nikto
meeting a little bit condemned coverage
to your mind is just like that don't get
bossy with your mind you boots you slip
it up or something same MO nobody likes
it be be clever be a good sounding oh
hey oh I let's get one after meditation
decided so it is a lot okay okay all
right now you happy so it's just yeah
I'm happy
daya justice so what are we gonna do for
the next half hour let's just go back to
the meditation talk to your mind okay
all right so second solution which is
really the fifth solution to the second
problem okay bring your mind back what
was the second problem problemo
I lost the object I started thinking
about all right third problem say Tinga
Tinga by the way russian speakers don't
worry I will try to finish in the next
15 minutes maybe third problem it's
called sleepy mind and busy mind okay
third problem has two parts problem at
wilchester
sleepy mind and busy mind and leave
using a toy so you know I studied
meditation for 30 years on my teacher
and I lived with him in the same class
and I I told my one morning I told it he
said how's your meditation I don't know
I always get sleepy I told these guys
one day even I fell asleep I hit my head
on the wall miss to collapse I came to
breakfast with my teacher I have a big
bump on my head
he's very smart he's gassy Kashi Kashi
Superga she want the Queenie prestigio
soo progressions say ah looks like you
got sleepy problem number three you hit
your head on the wall right yeah he said
why you get so sleepy I said well I
didn't get my sleep last night you made
me fix the you know sidewalk I didn't
get my sleep last night then he said
every meditator needs to sleep well -
have a good meditation cars don't
practical me that's amused Maharashtra
was the passage that we made for ocean
Mindy dancing then I remember I asked
him can you teach me deep secret tantric
method not to sleep I am the worst in
Abu cheats secret no more glue book
almost possible in his fights he said no
he's the very famous answer to all my
questions
he hurt his throat in car accident
before I met him she loved he talks just
like Star Wars all the time don't ask me
for the secret method
I mean I said me method they're all
people have to sleep
even the big Lamas have to sleep if you
don't want to be sleepy in your
meditation try sleeping on your bed my
son Lee wisdom is not superpowers
so how to fix the third problem well
partly should get enough sleep don't eat
before meditation near your stupid me
that green drink is fantastic it will
give you energy during your meditation
you polish the more energy of every time
you look at me so you know but don't eat
food before meditation only yes see you
do period missing you the sleepy okay
the other problem 3b the second part of
the third problem is your mind is too
busy problem is to wash all solutions in
the toy it was mainly your mind wants to
think about what you have to do this
after this today
it's trying to think about what you have
to do today okay stove on but it's ty
you d like to change and again my
suggestion is don't try to block it like
you know it don't yell at your mind
nobody likes to be stop thinking about
what we have to do today I'm still I'm
certainly but then your mind will just
think more things you have to do
okay so learn to talk to your mind as
you should talk to your children know
Jesus go but it's the same imam Cox's I
mean it's me
because the mind that doesn't meditate
is very similar to
a bad kid that most Katarina coaches
make it serious but doesn't pluck
American Co oh I mean you're gonna do
this in this in this in this just after
your meditation after humanity pause
let's focus on the okay so don't fight
with your mind you will lose we
progressed top tier mine yeah let's
let's think about it after meditation
you know we will stay in the meditation
seat and we will have a special post
meditation meditation about other things
we have to do today posting its own
absurd iniative Stoller's now let's go
back to our meditation okay so now the
classic solution for problem number
three yeah problem in our dream it's
called the smoke alarm yeah so we have
this special machines when there's smoke
in the room the the the machine whenever
Veronica enchiladas so you you gotta
have a mental smoke alarm means dilated
so you should install one now
I did promise each other okay and that
smoke alarm goes off it watches the
month that's what happened to me and
John pretty sure number 18 we meditate a
lot theorem we put the smoke alarm up
here we use it a lot it overheated
that's how you can tell the great
meditator that smoke alarm has two jobs
Oh a detector they mean is clear about
it if I get sleepy yes yeah let you know
as a surprise if I start thinking about
all the things I have to do today
yes and I do miss it we shall come you
know this one is do then the smoke alarm
goes Danger Danger PPP Danger Danger
[Music]
then there's some other subjects we we
can study later about subtle dumbest and
obvious et mr. Abu Musa said proud tone
cool some limits we're gonna go to
problem number four say do me
chiba-chiba do me cheaper do Nietzsche
so if you're married you know about
smoke alarms yes the vision Apple is
Amazon with night to protect erythema
smoke alarm in your house never go off
during the day always go up when you're
sleeping human is about with no map see
dust Rabat wait cut away
I believe it I think they put something
in the factory they put some clock
inside when the battery gets low and it
goes peep
you know that pretty beep every 20
seconds the most irritating sound for
sleep which exists happening you have
the berry Garlow and it goes beep then
you're like you know did you hear
something
you both wanted to know yeah let's go
back to sleep that's just a baby then
there's this fight you know husband wife
fight who's gonna put the battery in
this mope I just need that equal listen
I have important meeting tomorrow I need
to sleep that means you put Barry you
know right now what's the most stupid
thing you can both do at that moment ok
Sam I go polish cut the most results
with money on nobody takes
responsibility uniqueness about business
let's just go back to bed
we'll fix it in the morning all right
that's do me cheaper it do me cheaper
we'll fix it later then you both have
bad sleep all night
I mean if it goes that's okay but this
beep beep so the worst thing you can do
is just remember for
don't take action when you have to take
action we need that's problem number
four guess what's the solution oh god I
think our coalition
so homework question 4 is very easy
somebody has to get out of bed and put a
battery in the smoker and somebody has
to go into the mind and tell their mind
to shut up in a nice way don't be sleepy
don't think about donuts one chicken
that's why that teaches that don't think
about monkeys okay so that one's easy
okay now we're almost finished
and again we're giving this special
class just for you Gold Club people
because you are so cool in the whole
world you are the best Organization for
fundraising ACIP thank you any more yeah
be safe with us I did it Sam across
Natalie that's a meet across the border
and thank you too Maria and her husband
Peter thank you for organizing it's a
lot of work and we're very grateful my
CDs are valid a Mogan about this
possible and we are actually using the
books which you save you know something
negative is positive so we can go deeper
and deeper if we have more books and
they have covers okay now the last
problem number five it's very cool
so when I started in our diamond
business business we had only three
people and we have a tiny little office
with one small table Mikra office
against alone
we had three diamonds on diamonds we
tried to sell one then next day still
three times later we do we process
300,000 diamonds every day probabilities
that this is a mass of cars dating and
we became the one of the largest jewelry
companies and it was the largest time
Joey company in the world
it's a blossom a group known as the
companion of meeting what's the secret
meditation we know the five problems we
know the eight solutions and we used
them okay all day long okay we are
meditating on the mind is focus okay
problem number five you are very lucky
if you get it probably monomer PES mom
oh she will be obviously within your the
Barossa see why i talk about the diamond
company
which reminds me we had a big factory
why should we make 30,000 rings every
day we found out later every woman
average every woman in America has five
of our rings my part almost knowledge
top stratum cars the Americans causation
is actually one lady has ten one lady
doesn't have any you know but average
every woman in America has five of our
changed my Medicaid then the fact is
very big you know and the factory
manager was a very funny guy his name's
Kenny Lautman he's from New York
he taught from New York what is New York
a was that Kenny Lautman
but maybe I'll get in trouble till New
York people they talk like that
you're kyani what that regardeth maybe
you know someone who talks like that
they don't say coffee this is quality
you want some quality I need so much
coffee
why am I talking about that which my
why do the factory manager the
fact we men is a vote deserve what
mechanics that vote done
he always say listen geeky Michael if it
ain't broken don't fix it yes follow me
Chobani
okay very famous factory manager it
looks like that machines making noise
you know if it ain't broken don't fix it
yes the Islam Allah nice Revelator
in English we say don't mess with it man
Liscombe aquarium in the Narrows come
no new am I don't try to fix it
this planet okay leave it if it breaks
fixing yes llamas but it is yes what's
problem number five
okay problem on the merits you tried to
interfere with the meditation when it's
already going well
we put deities is prevalent mediate
Otsuka tree eat tacos refresh order now
you guys are not gonna have this problem
but just in case in the future
this year the meditation is going very
smooth tell the smoke alarm
take the battery out of the smoke alarm
okay don't do not check the meditation
when the meditation is flowing let the
meditation so what's solution number
fire question you better say it now say
it with a New York accent if it ain't
broke don't fix it okay so that
concludes our special Gold Club
meditation teaching there's lots more
you can learn you can learn to be a
meditation teacher with Tim and the
other Sigma other assistants see he is a
tricky case I with the help of Peter and
Maria Palmer should be primary they will
bring teacher training to Europe I need
and we look forward to you this year the
same rope a proper little crane in it to
karate
okay this year due out this year okay so
all right in the meantime you you cannot
teach meditation unless you are
meditating
don't try to fake it the student can
smell you teach the five problems very
nice solution very nice but you're
nervous unpleasant person then the
student is like Dharma Quixote
they have logic they are teaching
meditation they are nervous and they get
upset easily oh and you checked me
that's an in your digital cost reverses
therefore they are not meditating so you
can start your meditation teacher
training today
I don't watch that soon I check the boy
dreams delirium and do your meditation
okay thank you for listening
[Applause]
we're gonna go to the homeworks there's
some we've been skipping around so we
can have a nice show for the Spanish
speakers and the Russian speakers and
now we got to go back and let's make
sure we covered all the homework
questions okay
so I'm gonna just go back through the
homeworks and it's that I'm gonna pick
out the questions we didn't talk about
I'm on homework number five there's one
question we didn't finish say nature
Stelter March our soldier sorry nature
Salcha nature so these are three kinds
of fixation on the object your your your
mind is glued to the object by three
different levels okay your mind is good
today we talked about it a little bit
yesterday when we talked about the kiss
in the movie okay
now we're gonna go to more details on
the kiss in the movie okay
so nature means staying on the object
okay if you want to use a fancy word you
can say fixation you're fixated on the
object okay you have fixation are you
eating are you eating popcorn yes where
where are you eating popcorn at the
movie you're in the movie okay you're
watching the movie are you watching it
very closely
not until the kiss comes okay so that's
called nature nature means are you at
the movies yes I'm at the movies okay
okay got it then salchow means a
fixation with clarity
and they the example they give in the
scripture is this is nature okay you're
you're kind of holding the you are
holding the object but not so seriously
okay got it then sell cha means better
but not very strong okay then saying are
cha no chance okay
like done okay here's the nature nature
sell cha cha cha okay this is when they
kiss kiss this is when they're getting
ready to kiss this is the whole movie
okay are you in the movie yes that's
called nature I'm sitting in the movie
then sell cha they are getting close
enough to kiss that the popcorn slowed
down and then are cha
they are kissing and no one's eating
popcorn okay got it three levels of
fixation okay
gnar is an interesting word in Tibetan
dr. word you want to explain it do you
remember that's too bad yeah in it's a
it's a cool word in it means certain
kinds of steel will keep the sharpness
and some kinds of steel don't stay sharp
okay so some kind of steel the mass the
mass steel not the mask the mask
it keeps the sharp okay you use it many
times it will stay sharp that's corner
that's come it we say that knife has not
okay so if you're meditation it always
stays sharp and it cuts the object
easily that's called nor China okay one
moment in the movie
yeah when they're comin around they
never stay on that part very long they
never show the whole kiss okay I don't
know why okay this team they finished
homework five we finished homework oh
here's a good question on homework 6
okay which I didn't give you when you
get sleepy and we talked about it
briefly sanctifies a stupa how to bring
your mood up okay your mood is a little
bit low you feel tired like this
afternoon and your mood is not like
you're tired and you've been here for a
week and you know so your mood is not
it's not like you just had a coca-cola
or something you're just like okay then
there's three methods to bring up the
excitement in your mind okay three
methods in the ancient books for
bringing up and they're in order what
does that mean good yeah
try the I'm glad I didn't offer money
try the first try the first one if it
doesn't work go to the second one if
that doesn't work go to the third one if
that doesn't work quit and eat a big
dessert okay all right number one yeah
they say release release the focus a
little bit like go more towards the sky
and don't go to the sugar crystal okay
that's by the way that's why we're
learning those eight and I think when we
start to jump around those eight
then you have a different opinion what
does a are you see you say oh they're
not a flow yeah it's true they're not a
flow there are just exercises you know
first you do the twist and then you do
the stretch and then you do this
compression and abs okay there are
different exercises so if you skip
around you will have a better
understanding of what they are they are
not a flow they are not meant to be a
meditation okay when you get very good
at meditation and you want to warm up
you do your sock jung collect some good
karma confess some bad karma didn't do
some oh should go crystal okay I got I
got to do this this I don't know it's
just who I am I'm sorry JB will
appreciate it
[Music]
you
very try different
shine with the edge of my hand
okay-y it means that I my sugar crystal
and now I'm the sky
okay got it I'm standing next to Mount
Everest Hey but I knock it down what
else you got
Oh Mars haha yeah Mars finish you know
do you want me to take care of Jupiter
you know it means it's interesting
because he didn't meditate or maybe he
did I don't know but the idea is
suddenly your biggest your - big as the
whole world and you can hit the Mount
Everest and knock it over oh I'm sorry
and then sometimes your sugar crystal
and they lost you at Diamond Mountain
you know we're sketchy Michael I don't
know it's in one of these pieces of dirt
which one I don't know we lost track do
you get that feeling when you're going
to sugar crystal I feel like someone's
gonna anyone's gonna forget where I am
you know someone's gonna put me in their
teeth okay so if you get sleepy the
first method is expand go to the ocean
go to the sky okay five and six right
level five and six okay if you get
sleepy
that's the first thing to try okay
that's the first thing to try I'm as big
as a mountain I can chop it down with my
edge of my hand okay I love that line it
reminds me of formulas from okay if that
doesn't work
then think of something inspiring to you
okay think of something inspiring to you
we said someone you love right but
the classic example in Scripture is that
to think about in in the United States
right now I don't know there's 350
million people in this room there's a
hundred okay then so you are one in how
many you are one in three million out of
three million people you are one who has
karma to be here okay so if you feel low
in the meditation and you try to become
the ocean and you try to be on the sky
but you still don't feel I'm not talking
sleepy okay sleepy all you can do is
sleep okay but if you feel down you
don't feel inspired you don't feel like
meditating you started to wonder maybe I
wasting my time all over this desert you
know why did I why did I come here I
don't remember like maybe this is a big
waste of time you know and you start to
feel a little sad or I don't know not
depressed but pretty depressing almost
depressed and you're just down you know
and you don't feel very special
you don't feel dying around this very
special and you're like start to wonder
why spend all the money to come here and
then they want more money you know
they're always fundraising it's not
fundraising its fundraising
then they say think about the odds
against you being here okay there are
there are how many I said 2 3 million
people are not here and you are the most
special person out of 3 million people
okay so and and your body inside your
body there are 50,000 parts inside your
body there are 50,000 parts and you have
all of them and they are working and
they will not last forever
okay something one of the 50,000 parts
will break and then slowly you will get
cancerous okay
it's almost impossible for a human body
to not break okay we we made jewelry in
our factory jewelry has two parts the
diamond and the ring and it's not like a
computer it's not like a Toyota you just
have to put the diamond in the ring and
that's that's the whole production
process we had 30 percent failure 30
percent the Rings will break or and
something will happen the stone fell out
okay that's with two parts you have
fifty thousand okay for you to be alive
right now it's a miracle it's a total
miracle fifty thousand parts are
cooperating okay and it doesn't last
very long okay it's very unusual to be
healthy enough to come to Diamond
Mountain it's very unusual so you are
one in three million people probably
there's a couple hundred thousand people
who would like to be here but they can't
they physically they can't do it okay
got it
so you're supposed to feel special and I
got teachings this morning about I will
be ultimately happy if I just take care
of other people
okay so for have someone tell you that
you're one in ten million okay
you are one person in ten men who heard
the truth okay you want to be happy you
want to get what you want you want to
have a good life then focus on other
people take care of other people okay
and to hear that is more rare than to
get the fifty thousand pieces running
okay got it so you should feel a little
more inspired right now okay you you are
here you don't think you're special but
you are okay I can see it okay when I
see each person I know you're special
you are one in in the world you are one
in a hundred million in the world you
are one in a hundred million you each
person here you think you think you are
normal people but you are wrong
I can see something okay that you don't
see about yourself you're special
okay these person here you are one in a
hundred million okay so think about it
sometimes okay think about it you are so
special you practiced a million
lifetimes to get here okay okay so when
you think oh I feel tired today or I
don't you know why did I come out here
in the desert they don't have a shower
then by the way don't complain about the
shower because they will ask you for
money oh yeah we're gonna put a shower
we just need five thousand dollars so
just be quiet about the show
I okay without you oh I'm fine no
problem in the meditation thing I'm
special okay that's all you are special
okay you just didn't think about it from
here I can see I can see your face I can
see okay okay if that doesn't work okay
there's a emergency message and they say
go take a walk okay and that's it's
called emergency method you're allowed
to break your meditation if you have to
you are loud okay
a good meditator will sometimes take a
wall so their meditation will be better
okay so it's a method it's approved Jing
sutra method okay if you totally having
a bad day then then for goodness sake
get up take a walk okay don't don't sit
there and have a bad day okay get up
break the meditation because that's the
best thing you can do okay emergency
emergency emergency emergency okay they
give you three four choices number one
take a long walk number two go sit under
a tree that's cooler than your room
number three walk to a high place like
we have lots here we don't have any
level place next to me so anywhere you
go you're gonna go up so go to the top
of a mountain and just look at look at
this beautiful place okay and so this is
very lucky to be a dynamo okay that's a
very famous meditation solution is to go
to the top of the mountain walk you know
here it's not so far it's a 10-minute
15-minute walk walk to the top of one of
these ridges and just
look around and that improves your
meditation okay
all right and the last one he said did I
say it's throw water on your face okay
throw water on your face
my my cabin the hot water is broken and
every time I take a shower my mind gets
very clear yeah I don't know why bad
words come out when the cold water hits
your back it doesn't come out when you
hit the front okay and I don't know why
in the desert the water is so cold I
can't figure it out okay anyway okay now
suppose you are my next homework
question there are also three methods to
calm your mind down okay and usually
somebody said something to you okay
somebody said you're stupid or you know
there's some problem usually problem
with the other meditators the favorite
meditation upsetter
is the other meditators okay it's all
the same every meditation center the
main meditation problem is to other
meditators okay somebody will upset you
and your mind is shaky right and you
can't stop thinking but how do you slow
down the mind how do you calm down my
three traditional methods number one
again expand the meditation use the
empty space use the ocean get out of a
tight focus open up the focus open up
the focus okay you can imagine being on
a mountain okay top of a mountain
if your mind is still too busy and bla
bla bla bla bla bla then there's a very
famous solution start making a list of
all the people you know who died okay
start making a list in your mind of all
the people you know who died and you
when you're younger it's a shorter list
when you're my age it gets longer okay
so I used this in my three-year retreat
I actually kept a piece of paper with
dead people's name on it and I started
with four or five friends who died and
in my when I was in college or high
school and and then I couldn't think of
many you know and then I thought well
yeah there's the other guy yeah there's
one more and then suddenly it's a
hundred people and I'm like oh my god
it's a lot you know so when you talk to
my when I talk to my old lady she's like
they're all dead all my friends are dead
I'm the last one you know so then your
mind will come down okay yeah some other
meditator looked at you today you know
when you're in a deep retreat with the
hundred other people 50 other people
right JB how you insult somebody you're
like and then they're like you know okay
then you for two days you can't forget
it I can't believe he at me and she also
at me start to think about death okay
then that other stuff seems small then
other problems oh I have a I have my
showers cold water yeah but your mother
died okay I got it
okay got it it brings your mind down now
if that doesn't work traditionally start
counting your breaths again start
counting your breath again
- - you can go - I'll be done with
school just count your best okay good
we finished that that finishes homework
six